<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mobile | iwantmyreal.name]]></title>
  <link href="http://iwantmyreal.name//blog/categories/mobile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://iwantmyreal.name//"/>
  <updated>2013-09-18T11:00:39+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://iwantmyreal.name//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sam Davies]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Art of Custom UI Controls]]></title>
    <link href="http://iwantmyreal.name//blog/2013/09/18/the-art-of-custom-ui-controls/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-18T10:44:00+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://iwantmyreal.name//blog/2013/09/18/the-art-of-custom-ui-controls</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At various different events towards the end of 2013 I presented my thoughts on
how to build custom UI controls for mobile devices.</p>

<p>UI controls are really important to designers, developers and users as they
establish a common vocabulary which enables code/ui reuse between distinct
projects. Putting the effort in up-front, with the UX design, the API design and
the software architecture can save vast amounts of effort further down the line.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>Creating custom controls doesn’t just have to be about providing the functionality
to people outside your team - your other dev users could be yourself in 6 months
time. It’s a lot easier to reuse a control which was designed to be suitably
generic as opposed to trying to bastardise an incredibly situation-specific
example.</p>

<p>I have put the slides I presented at <a href="http://360iDev.com">360iDev</a> in Denver
up only for you to view below. I presented a similar version of the talk in other
fora - including Melbourne Monthly Mobile Meetup, and the Sydney Mobile Meetup.</p>

<script async="" class="speakerdeck-embed" data-id="e6d4ee90fc9e013049591e80c2aa53be" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" src="http://iwantmyreal.name///speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"></script>

<p>The presentation has an accompanying iOS project - ShinobiKnob, which is built
around the principles discussed. The source for this is on GitHub at
<a href="https://github.com/sammyd/ShinobiKnob">sammyd/ShinobiKnob</a>. I encourage you to
take a look at it - have a play, fork it, raise some issues, fix them ;) etc.</p>

<p>I’d love to hear any feedback you have - hit my up on twitter 
<a href="https://twitter.com/iwantmyrealname">@iwantmyrealname</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
